Onubogu Chibuikem



nickchibuikem@gmail.com



+2348066060467



linkedin.com/in/onubogu-chibuikem-883711159



https://potfoilo.vercel.app/

Summary

Hi I am Onubogu Chibuikem Onyedikachukwu. I am a talented software engineer with 6 years of experience in software engineering working with a variety of tools such as:

Javascript, ReactJs, NodeJs, Typescript, SQL/NoSQL databases and AWS.

Over my years as a software engineer:

- I have built full web applications from scratch till deployment.
- I have maintain and improve user experience for a startup with over \$75 million seed funding.
- I have Lead development teams to deliver cutting edge projects.
- I mentor junior developers on best practices.

I build cutting edge products that are beneficial to the end-users using the latest industry practice and pattern in my field.

You can rely on me to help you and your business achieve goals when software is needed.

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

Kafene

Apr 2021 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

Kafene is a mission driven fin-tech company with the goal of empowering flexible ownership solutions.

Compile and analyse data, processes, and codes to troubleshoot problems and identify areas for improvement.

Collaborate with the front-end developers and other team members to establish objectives and design more functional, cohesive codes to enhance the user experience.

Liaising with developers, and other stakeholders to identify and implement new features.

Collaborating with Front-end developers to integrate user-facing elements with server-side logic.

Review and merge backend related PRs.

423

Senior Software Engineer

Enyata

Apr 2021 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

Currently working with a team in New York to maintain a Fintech product and building internal products.

Building reusable code and libraries for future use.

Build high-quality reusable code that can be used in the future

Liaising with developers, and other stakeholders to identify and implement new features.

Promoted twice within my first year for being customer focused and producing results

Full Stack Developer

Freelance

Jul 2019 - Present (3 years 2 months +)

Build high-quality reusable code that can be used in the future

Develop functional and sustainable web and mobile applications with clean codes.

Troubleshoot and debug applications

Manage cutting-edge technologies to improve applications

Senior Full stack web developer

AK Infotech Solutions Ltd. (AKI Solutions)

Feb 2021 - Mar 2021 (2 months)

Mentored junior developers on programming and best coding practice

Integrate third-party systems via APIs.

Collaborate on a daily basis with other team members to understand business requirements and user experience goals and pain points.

FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

CJGrandExchange

Mar 2020 - Feb 2021 (1 year)

Conceived and built optimised landing pages in ReactJs.

Integrated payment gateway and cross-browser compatibility which improved marketing by 50%.

Integrate third-party systems via APIs.

Continuously work to bolster front-end and back-end design and implementation processes in order to improve quality and efficiency.

Develop new user-facing features

Ensures the technical feasibility of product designs



Full Stack Developer

Errandboy

Mar 2019 - Sep 2019 (7 months)

Worked on a web application that utilized HTML, JavaScript, CSS3, React, Laravel and MySQL.

Write and review testable, scalable codes that support and enhance single page data visualisations.

Build modular, reusable components, codes, features and libraries for future use.

Support and nurture front end real-time feeds and APIs to ensure that data renders with little delay.

FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

Dependable Orientals Ltd

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019 (6 months)

Designed and implemented a web application in PHP(Laravel) that was focused on connecting recruiters with job seekers.

This application cut setup time by 98% and significantly reduced human error.

Compile and analyze data, processes, and codes to troubleshoot problems and identify areas for improvement.

Liaising with stakeholders to identify and implement new features.

Junior Freelance Web Developer

Freelance

Oct 2016 - Nov 2018 (2 years 2 months) Built applications based on client requirements

Education



削 Nnamdi Azikiwe University

Bachelor of Science - BSc, Computer Science 2015 - 2019 Programmer.

Licenses & Certifications



in JavaScript: Patterns - LinkedIn

Skills

MySQL • Firebase • GitHub • PostgreSQL • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • HTML • JavaScript • JavaScript Libraries • JavaScript eXtension (JSX) • Embedded JavaScript (EJS)